Patricia Mukiri Mwithiga, B.A Communication, M.A International Studies

P.O. Box 78861-00507 Nairobi, Kenya Tel: +254.727.872.498 E-mail: mukiri7@gmail.com

Skype: Patricia. Mwithiga

Career Statement

Patricia Mwithiga works on regional economic communities and the opportunities they present small sized economies in Africa in overcoming their socio economic challenges. She has in particular focused on regional integration within the East Africa Community. Her work on the challenges of regional economic communities within the East African Community has been published by Palgrave publishers (2015) and she has been a presenter at the United Nations Economic Conference 2013. Patricia continues to carry out research on topics related to economic development within Sub Sahara Africa, in particular with focus on financial inclusion and the impact of mobile money in advancement of financial inclusion and elimination of inequality in Africa. Other areas of her focus and research are social security in reducing poverty and enhancing equality. Ms Mwithiga has eight experience in stakeholder engagement, research and advocacy in advancing policy formulation. She is an excellent relationship builder with extensive experience in the engagement of both private sector and governments.

Please see my education and experience in various roles outlined below;

Languages

English French (Learning) Kiswahili

Education and Training

Daystar University, Athi River, Kenya Bachelor of Arts in Communication, June 2008.

University of Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya Master in International Studies, December 2011.

Core Courses: International Economic Law, International Business Law, Diplomacy.

Publications and Presentations

Presenter at the African Economic Conference 2013, Johanesburg, South Africa. Conference Theme: African Regional Integration.

Published Works:

The challenges of regional integration in the EAC (2002-2010). Publication by Palgrave Macmillan (22 Dec. 2014)

Professional Experience

September 2013- January 2015: **Membership Services Coordinator, Federation of Kenya Employers**

Website: <u>www.fke-kenya.org</u>. The Federation of Kenya Employers is an employers' organization that supports the interests of employers within Kenya and the larger East African Community. The organization provides support through consultancy, training and policy formulation on labour laws, engaging government at a tripartite level. I provided support by developing regional and country lobby advocacy strategies to ensure recruitment of new employers and retain existing members.

May 2010- August 2013: Program Officer (Business Development & Partnerships), Kenya Red Cross Society

Website: <u>www.kenyaredcross.org</u>. The national society of the Red Cross in Kenya is involved in disaster relief programs throughout Kenya from emergency operations, human and health development to hunger and food security. I coordinated fundraising efforts through the sale of membership subscriptions and training to raise funds for the Red Cross disaster kitty.

Relevant Consultancies and Internships

Jan 2009- Oct 2009: Lobbying Consultant, Kenya ICT Federation

Website: www.ictak.or.ke. Lead consultant in charge of lobbying for the adoption of the Kenya Communication Amendment Act 2008. Organizing meetings with members of Kenyan parliament and engaging them on formulated position paper.

June 2007- October 2008: Intern, Office of the President (Kenya)

References

Prof. Martin Nguru
Senior Lecturer (Project Supervisor)
Institute of Diplomacy and International Studies (IDIS)
University of Nairobi
ngurumw@hotmail.com
0722874864

Mr. Isaac Kiema
Projects Manager
Federation of Kenya Employers
ikiema@fke-kenya.org
0710330095

Mr. Andrew Gargule PhD Resarch Candidate Universitat Bern agargule@hotmail.co.uk 0712940063